hello today we're talking about L by
works the creator of Mickey Mouse so our
story starts in 1919 in Kansas City USA
Walt Disney was the draftsman of I works
was an animator up goes hey Walt
what if we were to put a live-action
person into an animated frame yes that's
it they create something called the
Alice comedies but there's no money in
it wall though is ambitious he goes off
to California and he goes as the head of
Universal animation Charles Mintz he was
like this is amazing I can use this but
the quality has to be as good Walt's
like up get out here ASAP
yo this is better than being in Kansas
City cuz Kansas City is like you could
like give me the deed to the city and I
still wouldn't even stay there he drives
the seven days to California he takes
these oh no let me back up at this point
obtain up with Oswald the Lucky Rabbit
so Oswald is great for universe and Walt
goes to Charles Mintz and he says listen
we are in killing it time for you to pay
us some more money
Mintz men's look somebody laughs I'm
gonna give you less money misko's huh
I have signed all of your animators and
I own Oswald
he's my Walt Disney vine from that day
not only will I ever not own any
character I created I will never not own
them Andy he said two up of you with me
and up yet again left with Walt Disney
and upset don't what are we doing wrong
and well it's like we need a character
up what do you got
what about a horse new what about doc
nope
what about I can't no man we got enough
cats
we got Felix the Cat there's a lot of
calves out there world you got what
about a mouse Walt sighs yeah let's do
that
but what happened next was all of AI
works okay so up locked himself in the
studio and he turns out 600 to 700
frames a day unheard of he did two
months of animation in two weeks and he
created a character Mickey Mouse he sat
down and drew that cartoon plain crazy
wall loves it but he goes you know what
we need something bigger and I was like
what if we could sync sound to it what
if we said our next cartoon where we
could see the action happening in the
time with the music
and what was again let's do sync so
so seemed so steamed milk so Steamboat
Willie comes out and it blows audiences
away they went I can see that mouse
whistling I can hear the mouse whistling
oh my god this mouse is whistling along
with what his mouth is doing us we sync
sound there were standing ovations
Mickey Mouse became an icon overnight he
was referenced in movies and songs and
it creates disney like this in
embellishes arm eyes to everybody they
know that this is like the game has
changed with the added pressures of
Mickey doing really well Disney you
wanted to oversee every bit of
production hey you gotta meet this
timing sheet and we got to be here by
then and productivity more now at a
party in Hollywood a little kid came up
to Walt Disney he's like hey mr. Walt
Disney I love Mickey Mouse would you
draw me a picture of well it's like sure
kid I'll try a picture Mickey Mouse and
he handed the paper to up I works and up
goes whoa are you kidding me this is
what no I'm outta here
where was I up and Walt Disney and up
starts I works animation crazy stuff
happened in his cartoons you know girls
dresses blow off and you know animals
would lose limbs like he was anarchy but
the Hays Commission comes in those are
the guys who were starting to put
limitations on what you couldn't
couldn't show and they were like this is
not gonna fly anymore
so that was the end of I works animation
a friend of herbs is working at Disney
Studios - he's like herbs out of work
you could use him Walt agrees to have AB
for lunch he says um I want you back
please come work for me and uh looks at
him and he says well I want to come back
and work for you but I will never work
for you in animation I want to work for
you in photographic effects and wall is
like yeah you're the guy for that come
and do that for me he was a rock star
for Walt he builds stuff so they could
do Mary Poppins the penguin dance he
wins a technical Oscar for that uh by
works had his hand in every single ride
at Disneyland creating the special
effects and hub died a Disney Legend so
this isn't real doesn't he ending or as
I like to think so I like to think this
is an I work sending cuz he was the man
dub what the kind of name sub
you